(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
約束その一
Promise number one
私以外の女とは 目を合わせないこと！
Do not make eye contact with any woman other than me!
約束その二
Promise number two
破った場合 法律とかは考えないものとします！
If you break it, I won't care about the law or anything!
本心なんて曖昧だね 独占禁止？上等！
True feelings are so vague. Antitrust? Bring it on!
（上等！）
(Bring it on!)
サーカスだって無い知恵絞り
Even a circus uses all its wits
ゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイだめ！
Absolutely, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely NO!
フラフラうつつ抜かすような人には
To someone who's always doting on others
ご機嫌なんてあげないないない
I won't give you any good humor, no, no, no
（お祭り！）命令です！ ゼッタイ王政始めました
(Festival!) It's an order! Absolute Monarchy has begun
よそ見しちゃって引き回し 処刑乱舞どんときた
Looking away means being dragged around. A flurry of executions, bring it on
ワガママだってファンファーレ
Even selfishness is a fanfare
夢中 １・２・３！ カーニバル
Immersed in it, 1, 2, 3! Carnival
ほら行け せっせっせーのよいっ！
Come on, go! Heave-ho!
男子でフェスティバル
A festival for the boys
それちょっと ずっちーな！
That's a bit unfair!
もっかい カーニバル
Once more, Carnival
私だけの特権 アイウォンチュー
My own exclusive privilege, I want you
ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
約束その三
Promise number three
他の女に「可愛い」って言わないこと！
Do not say "cute" to other women!
約束その四
Promise number four
破ったら「はりつけ」＆私に釘付け確定！
If you break it, you're guaranteed to be "crucified" & stuck on me!
崇拝だって純愛でしょ 革命前夜万歳！
Worship is pure love, right? The eve of the revolution, Banzai!
（万歳！）
(Banzai!)
王国だって変えちゃう未来
A future that could even change the kingdom
ゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイゼッタイ修正！
Absolute, absolute, absolute, absolute, absolute, absolute correction!
ヨリドリミドリね 素敵よね
So many choices, it's wonderful, isn't it?
お馬鹿さん
You dummy
心拍感に走らないないない
Don't let your heartbeat run away, no, no, no
（お祭り！）やきもちです！ ゼッタイ王政始めちゃうわ
(Festival!) I'm jealous! I'm starting the Absolute Monarchy
君を狙ってひきりなし 一般教養サイナラさ
Aiming for you incessantly, farewell to general knowledge
駆け引きだって祭り方
Even bargaining is a way of the festival
爆中 １・２・３！ カーニバル
Bursting in, 1, 2, 3! Carnival
それってどういう関係？
What kind of relationship is that?
男子でフェスティバル
A festival for the boys
そんなもの 三角関係！
That's a love triangle!
もっかい カーニバル
Once more, Carnival
取調べ 黙秘権 尋問中
Under investigation, right to remain silent, during interrogation
それさ！
That's it!
ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
ねぇ こんなこと言いたくないよ 本当は
Hey, I don't really want to say things like this, truth be told
だけど 本気で 伝えておけばよかったなってさ
But I thought I should have told you seriously
後悔したくないのよね
I don't want to regret it
（絶対的なのよね）わかって これも愛
(It's absolute, isn't it) Understand that this too is love
命令です！ ゼッタイ王政始めました
It's an order! Absolute Monarchy has begun
よそ見しちゃって引き回し 処刑乱舞どんときた
Looking away means being dragged around. A flurry of executions, bring it on
ワガママだってファンファーレ
Even selfishness is a fanfare
夢中 １・２・３！ カーニバル
Immersed in it, 1, 2, 3! Carnival
ほら行け せっせっせーのよいっ！
Come on, go! Heave-ho!
男子でフェスティバル
A festival for the boys
それちょっと ずっちーな！
That's a bit unfair!
もっかい カーニバル
Once more, Carnival
私だけの特権 アイウォンチュー
My own exclusive privilege, I want you
（お祭り！）どうやったって カーニバル
(Festival!) No matter what, it's a Carnival
ゼッタイ王政カーニバル！
Absolute Monarchy Carnival!
テンパテンパアップして ずっかんかんベンジョ
Getting all flustered, things are going crazy
あなたに申し出たいこと 悲しいこと あるのかしらね
The things I want to tell you, the sad things, I wonder if they exist
知らない笑顔の海に涙を
Into the sea of unknown smiles, my tears...
ドラマチックが足りてないからよ
Because our drama isn't dramatic enough
そんな苦にもつかないこと
Such trivial things
くだらないこと考えてばかりね
Thinking about nothing but meaningless things
雨が上がれば愛もその予報も
When the rain stops, love and its forecast
誰かのものになるんでしょう
Will probably belong to someone else
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部恋のためよ
Even the fake foundation is all for love
なのに一体全体どうしてどうして夏はデイハペナー
So why, oh why, is summer "Day Happener"?
不安定なカンペーラもどこまで行くの
How far will the unstable "Campella" go?
あなた一切合切空っぽになってしま
You'll become completely empty
冗談じゃないないわ
It's no joke
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が消えたってどうにもならないぜ
Even if that time vanishes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当なんてめくるめくほど
Vague truths, so dizzying
私をさらさらって今　点呼見え
Sweep me away, and now I see the sky's call
ちゃんちゃらおかしな事ばかりで
Nothing but ridiculous things
食指がピクリともしないわ
I don't feel like eating at all
実体のない感情ほっておいたって
Even if you leave intangible emotions alone
策略なんてありゃせんのに　何故？
There's no strategy, so why?
あーもうコリゴリよ　私の勝気な気質も
Ah, I've had enough of my headstrong nature
ちっと堪えて取り繕って　ああ、とうとう臨界点
Endure and keep up appearances, ah, finally at the critical point
年がら年中リップサービス
Lip service all year round
鈍感かましてはへきえき
I'm fed up with being insensitive
どんがら合唱フィールガールは
The noisy chorus "Feel Girl"
涙の目にも二
Is like a second layer to crying eyes
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいで
Now, because of the music in my head
あなたの話は1個も聞き取れない
I can't hear a single thing you're saying
少しはマトモなこと言ってイヤイ
Tell me something decent for once
回りだすターンテーブルに全部
Let the spinning turntable
忘れさせてよ
Make me forget everything
だけど一体全体どうしてどうして夏はデイハペナー
But why, oh why, is summer "Day Happener"?
不安定なカンペーラ消えないまんまね
The unstable "Campella" stays, never disappearing
あなた一切合切空っぽになってしま
You'll become completely empty
冗談じゃないないわ
It's no joke
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が消えたってどうにもならないぜ
Even if that time vanishes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当なんてめくるめくほど
Vague truths, so dizzying
私を今ー！
Me, now...!
冗談じゃないないわ
It's no joke
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が消えたってどうにもならないぜ
Even if that time vanishes, nothing can be done
不甲斐ないわ　感情なんて不条理で落とすだけ
I'm pathetic, emotions are just absurd things to drop
私と確かめ合ってよ今夜　アイアイヤ
Make sure with me tonight, ai-ai-ya
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が消えたってどうにもならないぜ
Even if that time vanishes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当なんてめくるめくほど
Vague truths, so dizzying
私をさらさらって今　点呼見え
Sweep me away, and now I see the sky's call
はい！ということで、改めまして、みんなこんばんわいしょーい！
Alright! Once again, good evening, everyone! Washoi!
ホロライブの清楚担当みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりでーす！
I'm the pure idol of Hololive, Natsuiro Matsuri!
今日はね、皆さん来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you all for coming today!
本日のライブは「今夜はdance the night」！
Today's live is "Tonight is dance the night"!
これ英語だからさ、あんま覚えられないんだけど
Since it's in English, I can't really remember it well
ということでね、あの、ダンスをめちゃ頑張っておりますよ。
So, I'm working really hard on the dancing.
いきなりさ、すごい「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」なんて難しいダンスをしちゃったりなんかして
I suddenly did such a difficult dance like "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous"
気合いがね、みなぎっておりますでございます。
You can see how fired up I am.
はい、ということで、皆さんダンス映え映えですのでね
Yes, so, since the dancing is very photogenic
スクショも撮って、
Take screenshots too,
ハッシュタグ「#今夜は」漢字と平仮名、「dance the night」英語で呟いてください
Please tweet with the hashtag "#今夜は" in Kanji/Hiragana and "dance the night" in English
お願いします、いっぱいね、ツイートして、ぜひトレンドに挙げて、まつりのエゴサをワクワクさせてください！
Please tweet a lot, get it trending, and get me excited for my ego-search!
ということでね、早速なんですけど
So, without further ado
ここからは何と、豪華ゲストによるコラボパートに行っちゃいましょう！
Let's head into the collaboration part with some amazing guests!
いやー、今回は誰が出るかな？どうなのかな？何の曲を歌うのかな？
Who will show up this time? How will it be? What song will they sing?
ワクワクが止まりませんね！
I can't stop being excited!
はい、より一層スクショ、カメラを止めるなでよろしくお願いします！
Yes, even more screenshots, and please "Don't Stop the Camera"!
それでは行きますよ。コラボパートスタート！
Alright, here we go. Collab part, start!
ハッピーライフカーニバル / 作詞・作曲・編曲：田中秀和
Happy Life Carnival / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Hidekazu Tanaka
あらら今年もまた終わってしまいますね
Oh dear, this year is coming to an end again
おやおや早いですね
My, my, that was fast
世界各国ついつい師走も走り回っ
Running around even in December all over the world
アン・ドゥ・トロワでヘイ・ヘイ・ホ
Un, deux, trois, and hey, hey, ho
本年はいかがでしたか？
How was this year for you?
良いも悪いも色々さ
Good or bad, there were various things
来年もまたよろしくね
Please look forward to next year too
共に歌い踊り明かそう
Let's sing and dance the night away together
Hey Boys&Girls up hands, Yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey Boys & Girls, put your hands up, Yeah, yeah, yeah
笑い合いながら
While laughing together
Hey Boys&Girls up hands, Yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey Boys & Girls, put your hands up, Yeah, yeah, yeah
時に涙流して
Sometimes shedding tears
夢や希望をいつまでも見ていたいな
I want to keep dreaming and hoping forever
Get dreaming dreaming come with me
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
手を叩きながら
While clapping our hands
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
心弾ませて
With our hearts bouncing
歌を歌おう どこまでも響かせて
Let's sing a song, letting it resonate everywhere
Get singing singing
Let's go do it chuck chuck chuck
気が付けば またたく間に過ぎる日々の中で
In the days that seem to pass by in the blink of an eye
がむしゃらに行きます
I'll go with all my might
新しい波がワクワクを押し寄せてきます
A new wave of excitement is surging towards us
Top-side 存分にやっていこう
Let's go all out on the top-side
喜びも悲しみも また
Joy and sorrow too
山あり谷あり色々さ
There are ups and downs, all sorts of things
いつだってエキサイトな日々を送れますように
May you always lead exciting days
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
足取り合わせて
Keeping step with each other
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
時におどけてみても
Even if we act silly sometimes
愛を胸に いつまでも輝いていたい
With love in my heart, I want to shine forever
Get thinking thinking make a wish
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
迷った時には
When you're lost
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
手を差し伸べるよ
I'll reach out my hand to you
ともに支え歩いていければいいな
It would be nice if we could walk together, supporting each other
Help me join hands Happy Life Carnival
同じものを愛す 僕ら同志よ
We are comrades who love the same things
同じ時を生きる 私たち同志よ
We are comrades living in the same era
同じ星に生まれた 僕ら同志よ
We are comrades born on the same planet
愛し争いたからこそ美しい
Beautiful precisely because we loved and struggled
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
笑い合いながら
While laughing together
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
時には涙して
Shedding tears sometimes
夢や希望をいつまでも見ていたいな
I want to keep dreaming and hoping forever
Get dreaming dreaming come with me
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
いつも君らしく君のまま
Always be yourself, just as you are
Clap your hands yeah yeah yeah
ずっと笑顔のままでいて
Please keep smiling forever
明日も明後日も その次のまた次の日も
Tomorrow, the day after, and the day after that too
Get forever Let's go do it chuck chuck chuck
ちゃんと締めるよ
I'll wrap it up properly
はーい
Okay
せーの！
One, two!
それではまた次回 See you next time oh oh
Until next time, See you next time oh oh
はい！というわけでハッピーライフカーニバルでした！
Yes! So that was Happy Life Carnival!
イェーイ！ おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
あきちゃん改めて おめでとう。おめでとう！
Aki-chan, once again, congratulations. Congrats!
ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to the live!
あー、もう汗かいたから、もう帰ろかな。
Ah, I'm all sweaty now, so I think I'll head home.
ちょっと待って。ねねち帰っていい？ ねねち帰っていい？
Wait a second. Can Nenechi go home? Can Nenechi go home?
いや、ダメでしょ！ 一緒にいようよ。
No, you can't! Let's stay together.
嘘、嘘、嘘だよ。大好きだよ。
Liar, liar, I'm kidding. I love you guys.
えー待って、アキロゼの方、大好きだよ。
Eh wait, I love Akirose more.
だから一緒にいたかったんだ。なんかちょっと軽い。
That's why I wanted to be with you. It feels a bit light.
分かった、誕生日だからそういうこと言ってあげて。
I get it, say those things because it's her birthday.
まあ、まあいいか、よかった。
Well, well, okay, I'm glad.
ということでね、結構難しい振りで移動とかもありながらね
So, with pretty difficult choreography and movement,
すごいダンスレッスンも頑張ってくれて
they both worked really hard in dance lessons.
まじねねちのあそこの、なんかこういうとこが好き
Seriously, I love that part of Nenechi's, like this part.
できないだよ、全然。
I can't do it at all.
鳥さん、鳥さんって言いながらやってたの。
She was doing it while saying "Birdie, birdie".
めちゃめちゃ可愛くて好きですね。
It was so cute, I love it.
あきちゃん本当にマジで上手い。
Aki-chan is truly, seriously good.
そんなこと、そんなことはないですよ。
That's not... that's not true at all.
おねえちゃん感があってさ。
She has that big sister vibe.
よく見ると、こう、一生懸命みんなに合わせようとしてる。
If you look closely, she's trying her best to match everyone.
え、でも二人はアイドル、めっちゃアイドル感あってめっちゃ可愛い。
Eh, but you two are so idol-like, you look like real idols and are so cute.
アキロゼは可愛い。大人の、大人な感じ。よかった。
Akirose is cute. She has a mature, grown-up feel. I'm glad.
最後の、ウォウウォウのさ、この揺れてるのを横に感じてさ
At the end, with the "woah woah", I felt this swaying next to me...
ここね、こだわりポイントだったんだよね。
This part was a point of focus, wasn't it?
いや、いい。風吹いてた。風吹かした。
Yeah, it was great. The wind was blowing. I made the wind blow.
そう、この曲はね、マジずっとやりたかったの。
Yeah, I've seriously wanted to do this song forever.
そう、結構やっぱ振りも難しいし
Yeah, the choreography is pretty hard after all.
誰とならいいかなーってめっちゃ考えて、お二人になりましたので。
I thought a lot about who would be good for it, and it ended up being you two.
嬉しい。信頼して任せました。
I'm so happy. I trusted you both and left it to you.
やったー！
Yay!
しかも雰囲気もさ、めっちゃ合ってるよね、
And the atmosphere really matches,
ここのね、ステージと。マカロンとかあったりして。
the stage here. With the macarons and everything.
みんなちょっとずつ違うピンクだし。
Everyone's wearing a slightly different pink.
あ、そうだ！ピンク、ピンク、ピンク...
Oh, that's right! Pink, pink, pink...
グラデーションみたいになってる。
It's like a gradient.
ねー。可愛い。薄いから濃くなっている。
Yeah. It's cute. It goes from light to dark.
本当だ。濃厚ピンク。
You're right. A rich pink.
ねー。めちゃめちゃ可愛い。ありがとうございますね。
Yeah. It's super cute. Thank you so much.
素敵な誕生日になりました。
It's been a wonderful birthday.
ということで、次も頑張るわ、まつり。
So, Matsuri's going to do her best on the next one too.
頑張れー！
Do your best!
ちょっと2人からの愛を頂戴？
Can I have some love from you two?
ラブッチュー！
Love-chuu!
にゅー！
Nyu!
やったー！頑張りまーす！
Yay! I'll do my best!
頑張れー！
Do your best!
人たちの気持ちを知ったように描いた道
A path drawn as if I knew people's feelings
ビジネスライクな足で予習
Preparing with business-like steps
言葉の意味を分かってるのか
Do you even understand the meaning of the words?
こっちが心配になってくる
I'm starting to get worried
不意に見せてる所は可愛い
The parts you show unexpectedly are cute
そのツケをどこに持ってくの
Where are you taking the bill for that?
自慢ばなしを聞きに来たんじゃない
I didn't come here to listen to your boasting
あなたは私をどうしたいの
What do you want to do with me?
時間だって楽じゃないんだし
Time isn't easy either
響かない言葉並べないで
Don't line up words that don't resonate
惨めなとこ見せないで
Don't show me your miserable side
このまま返してもいいの
Is it okay to just send you back like this?
恋の始まりは理屈じゃないよ
The beginning of love isn't logical
全然始まりそうにない
It doesn't seem like it's starting at all
熱しやすくて冷めやすいんだろ
You're quick to heat up and quick to cool down, right?
そんなこと誰も聞いてないでしょ
Nobody's asking for that, right?
無駄に気負って探り落としてる
Needlessly pushing yourself and searching
がっかりさせないで　もうクレイジー
Don't disappoint me, it's already crazy
追いかけたくなるくらいにさせてよ
Make me want to chase after you
あなたは私をどうしたいの
What do you want to do with me?
行くあてもない心が寂しい
My heart is lonely with nowhere to go
響かない心を動かして
Move my heart that doesn't resonate
私だって笑ってたいの
I want to be laughing too
誰かこの扉を開けて
Someone, open this door
寂しさを隠してるわけじゃなくて
It's not that I'm hiding my loneliness
静かにさせてこんな私を
Let me be quiet, someone like me
自慢ばなしを聞きに来たんじゃない
I didn't come here to listen to your boasting
あなたは私をどうしたいの
What do you want to do with me?
時間だって楽じゃないんだし
Time isn't easy either
響かない言葉並べないで
Don't line up words that don't resonate
追いかけたくなるくらいにさせてよ
Make me want to chase after you
あなたは私をどうしたいの
What do you want to do with me?
行くあてもない心が寂しい
My heart is lonely with nowhere to go
響かない心を動かして
Move my heart that doesn't resonate
私だって笑ってたいの
I want to be laughing too
誰かこの扉を開けて
Someone, open this door
惨めなとこ見せないで
Don't show me your miserable side
このまま返してもいいの
Is it okay to just send you back like this?
はい！ということで、
Yes! So,
2人に来てもらいました！ありがとう！
I had these two come! Thank you!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy Birthday!
あ、今日じゃないけどね、おめでとう！
Oh, it's not today, but congrats!
そう、誕生日はね、7月22日だったんですけどね。
Yes, my birthday was July 22nd.
本日ちょっと遅れて、お祝いしていただきました。
I'm being celebrated a bit late today.
遅れてお祝いしてもいいじゃーん。
It's fine to celebrate late!
おめでとう！嬉しい！
Congratulations! I'm so happy!
二人はね、ちょっとかっこいい感じ合うかなと思って...
I thought you two would fit a cooler vibe...
...このステージで、はい、この曲を選びました。
...so I chose this stage and this song.
めちゃくちゃバランスがいい。思ってたよりも。
The balance is surprisingly good.
でしょ？
Right?
うん。
Yeah.
でも、ちょっとダンス難しいかなーと思いながら...
But I was worried the dance might be hard...
どうでした？
How was it?
ここが難しかった。
This part was difficult.
ダンス練習がね。
The dance practice, right?
ずっ、あっ、そこね！
That part there!
でもさ、みんな結構初めてのダンス練習の時も結構覚えてきてなかった？
But you all learned it pretty well at the first practice.
あ、そう、確かに。
Oh, that's true.
そうなんだよ。先生も「あ、できますね」みたいな。
Even the teacher was like, "Oh, you can do it."
ね、結構詰め詰めでやったのにね。
Even though it was a very tight schedule.
ねー。頑張りました。
Yeah, we worked hard.
本当にありがとうございますね。
Thank you so much.
いや、呼んでいただきありがとうございます。
No, thank you for inviting me.
はい。またちょっと次回とかも、呼ぶかもしれないので。
I might call you again next time.
誕生日ケーキ食べたいな。
I want to eat birthday cake!
食べたいな。
I want to eat it too.
まつりが出すの？
Is Matsuri paying?
しょうがないな。この後ホールケーキ一緒に食べようね。
Fine. Let's eat a whole cake together later.
やったー！
Yay!
まつりちゃんなんか優しいから。っていうか甘いからさ。
Matsuri is so kind. Or should I say, she's a softie.
おねだりしたら何でもくれるよ。
She'll give you anything if you beg.
え？そういうこと言う。
Eh? Don't say that...
うん。まあ何でもあげる。
Well, I'll give you anything.
じゃあ、家ちょうだい、家。
Then give me a house! A house!
え、いくら、いくらの...
Eh, how much... how much would it be?
まー、いくらだろう。
Well, I wonder how much.
一軒家、一軒家。
A house!
一緒に住む？あ、いいよいいよ。
Let's live together? Oh, okay.
じゃあいくらでも積んで。
Then put down as much as you want!
よかったねー、それ最高の誕生日プレゼントだね。
Awesome! That's the best birthday present.
やったー！
Yay!
トワ様もよかったら来てね。
Towa-sama, you come too if you'd like.
三人ですも。
It'll be the three of us.
あ、いい、ごめん。無理だ。
Oh, sorry. No can do.
え？
Eh?
あ、トワ先輩もいないならじゃあ無理だ。
If Towa-senpai isn't there, then I can't go either.
え、何で！？まつりだけじゃダメなの？
Eh, why!? Just Matsuri isn't good enough?
無理だ。誕生日なのに。
No way! And it's my birthday!
でも、この後もあるしね。
Well, you have more stuff after this, right?
一人になっても大丈夫だよ。
It's okay if you're alone!
じゃ、頑張ってね！またねー！
Good luck! See ya!
頑張るぅ...
I'll do my best...
行くぞー！
Here we go!
モノクロだらけの明日なんて
A tomorrow full of monochrome
空白だらけの世界なんて
A world full of blank spaces
笑顔さえも枯れちゃいそうで
Even smiles seem like they'll wither away
なんてったって耐えきれない
I just can't stand it!
虹色だらけの地図を描こう
Let's draw a map full of rainbow colors
キラキラだらけに塗りつぶそう
Let's fill it all with sparkles
夢の魔法使い目指して
Aiming to be a dream magician
今日も修行中
Still training today
魔法の呪文を唱えましょう
Let's chant the magic spell
カラフルマジックをご覧あれ
Behold the colorful magic!
よし！はっ！せい！ほっ！あ、それ！よいしょー！
Alright! Ha! Tei! Ho! There! Heave-ho!
はぇ？おえ？
Huh? Oh?
うわあー！
Uwaa!
行くよー！
Here I go!
マジカ ポパペルカ
Magica Popaperuka
見てみてみんなイッツショータイム
Look, everyone, it's showtime!
ワン・ツー・スリーで染め上げて
Dye it all in one, two, three
ビビットカラフル大作戦
Vivid Colorful Operation
だからマジカ ポパペルカ
So, Magica Popaperuka
夢色の世界にご招待
Inviting you to a dream world
笑顔咲かせるような
To make the smiles bloom
君だけの魔法をかけよう
I'll cast a spell just for you
内緒だよ
It's a secret!
チュ！
Chu!
時にはお薦めのステップで
Sometimes with recommended steps
優しいメロディに揺られ
Swaying to a gentle melody
輝く音色を奏でるのも
Playing a shining tone
なんてったって大好き
Is what I love the most
やっぱり早めに送れないで
Don't let it be delivered early after all
ワクワク心待ってくれない
The excitement won't wait in my heart
夢の魔法使い目指して
Aiming to be a dream magician
今日も修行中
Still training today
魔法のリズムを奏でましょう
Let's play the rhythm of magic
もう一つマジックをご覧あれ
Behold one more magic trick!
よし！はっ！せい！ほっ！あ、それ！よいしょー！
Alright! Ha! Tei! Ho! There! Heave-ho!
行くぞー！
Here we go!
ん？こら！
Hmm? Hey!
マジカ ポパペルカ
Magica Popaperuka
ほらほらみんなイッツショータイム
Look, look, everyone, it's showtime!
ワン・ツー・スリーで塗りまくれ
Paint it all in one, two, three
ビビットカラフル大作戦
Vivid Colorful Operation
だからマジカ ポパペルカ
So, Magica Popaperuka
夢色の世界にご招待
Inviting you to a dream world
涙吹き飛ばすような
To blow away the tears
弾けだす魔法唱えよう
I'll chant a bursting magic spell
本当だよ
It's true!
あれあれまだ私の
Wait, wait, has my charm
魅力が伝わってない？
Not reached you yet?
これだけじゃ終われない
It can't end with just this
最後にとびきりショータイム
Finally, the ultimate showtime
まだ信じてない人は
Those who still don't believe
お気をつけください
Please be careful
超最強の禁断呪文
The strongest forbidden spell
ハイパービビッパポパペルカ
Hyper Vivippa Popaperuka
テッテレー！やったぜー！
Tada! We did it!
マジカ ポパペルカ
Magica Popaperuka
見てみてみんなイッツショータイム
Look, everyone, it's showtime!
ワン・ツー・スリーで染め上げて
Dye it all in one, two, three
ビビットカラフル大作戦
Vivid Colorful Operation
だからマジカ ポパペルカ
So, Magica Popaperuka
夢色の世界にご招待
Inviting you to a dream world
テンポアップ　加速するような
Tempo up, as if accelerating
きみだけの魔法をかけよう
I'll cast a spell just for you
内緒だよ
It's a secret
チュッ
Chu!
5分前！
5 minutes before!
はい、アユミマジカルショータイムでしたー！
Yes, that was Ayumi Magical Showtime!
うわー！
Wow!
あっちー！
So hot!
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
いや、大丈夫でござる。改めてまして！
No, I'm fine degozaru. Once again!
はい！まつり先輩、この度は本当に本当にお誕生日、
Yes! Matsuri-senpai, for this occasion, really, really, on your birthday,
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
やったー！ありがとうー！
Yay! Thank you!
めちゃめちゃ激しい曲をね、風真にお願いして。
I asked Kazama to do a really intense song.
まあ、あの、ござるちゃんは、体力モリモリなんで、
Well, um, Gozaru-chan has tons of stamina,
まあ、できるだろうと思って。
So I thought you'd be able to do it.
いや、その信頼に応えられて本当によかったです！
No, I'm so glad I could live up to that trust!
いや、すごかったよ、ありがとうね！
No, it was amazing, thank you!
こちらこそ！まつり先輩と一緒に踊るのは、
The pleasure is mine! Dancing together with Matsuri-senpai...
そうだね。全体曲以外はない？
That's right. We haven't done it except for group songs?
そう、2人とかはね、全然ないから、嬉しかった！ありがとう！
Right, just the two of us, not at all. I was so happy! Thank you!
よかった！ありがとうございます！
I'm glad! Thank you very much!
ちょっとね、もうちょっと誕生日なんで、
Since it's my birthday and all,
ちょっとお願いを聞いてほしいんだけどいいかな？
I'd like to ask a small favor, is that okay?
お願い？
A favor?
お願い。お願い。お願い。
A favor. A favor. A favor.
あーちょっと可愛いな。もちろん、もちろん、もちろん！
Ah, that's a bit cute. Of course, of course, of course!
じゃあ、風真がちょっと、あの、
Then, Kazama, if you could, um...
告白とか、してもらって、いいかな？
...do a confession or something, would that be okay?
う、梅さんの入れ知恵ですか？それ。なんか...
I-Is this Ume-san's idea? That... It feels like...
告白させてください、だって。まつり先輩！
She says "Please let me confess." Matsuri-senpai!
お前に好かれたいんだよ、風真！
I want you to like me, Kazama!
えっ、好きかも、しれない...
Eh, I might... like you...
じゃあ、ちょっとガチ恋距離でお願いしていいですか？
Then, can I ask you to do it at a "gachikoi" distance?
ガチ恋距離でござるか？
At a "gachikoi" distance degozaru?
あ、あの「まつり」って言わなくていいから、
Ah, um, you don't have to say "Matsuri",
「君のことが好きだよ」系で。「君」で！
Just something like "I like you". Use "Kimi"!
待って、本当、本当、まつり先輩、誕生日プレゼントです！
Wait, really, really, Matsuri-senpai, it's a birthday present!
いや、そうです、そうです。もう、何回でも見返すんで、
No, yes, yes. I'll watch it over and over again,
「君」でお願いします！
So please use "Kimi"!
それでは、風真いろは、告白まで、
Now then, until Kazama Iroha's confession,
3、2、1、キュー！
3, 2, 1, cue!
君のことが...
I...
...好きだよ。
...like you.
きゃー！
Kyaa!
死ぬー！最高！
I'm gonna die! This is the best!
助けてー！尊すぎるー！
Help me! It's too precious!
ちょっと待って。危ない、誕生日に死ぬところだった。
Wait a second. That was dangerous, I almost died on my birthday.
すごい落としますよ、ドスって。
She fell so hard, like thud.
いや、でもこれで、このあとも頑張れるわ。
No, but with this, I can keep going afterwards.
本当でござるか？よかった！
Really degozaru? I'm glad!
いや、このあともね、楽しみにさせてもらいます。
No, I'm looking forward to what's coming next too.
頑張ってください！はい！
Please do your best! Yes!
改めて、お誕生日おめでとうございました！
Once again, happy birthday!
アドゥー！
Adieu!
きょうもハレバレ
作詞・作曲：ふわりP
Cheerful again today
Lyrics/Composition: Fuwari P
オイェイ！イェイ！
Oh yay! Yay!
アッフー！フッフー！
Ah-hoo! Hoo-hoo!
オイェイ！イェイ！
Oh yay! Yay!
時計の鐘が響く空
The clock bell echoes in the sky
今日もテンテケテンテンテン
Today too, tenteketen-ten-ten
それピンピキピンピンピン
That pinpikipin-pin-pin
カーテン開いて朝が
Opening the curtains, the morning...
そよぐテンテケテンテンテン
...breezes, tenteketen-ten-ten
のんてんてん
Non-tenten
陽だまりにあくびして
Yawning in a sunny spot
ななめに背伸びして
Stretching out at an angle
小鳥を眺めたら
If you look at the little birds
トースターに一枚パンを乗せて
Putting a slice of bread in the toaster
今日が始まる
Today begins
鮮やかに街は輝いている
The streets are brightly shining
キラキラと笑っている
They are smiling brilliantly
広場へと続く舗道が
The pavement leading to the square
緑色の髪揺らした
Shook its green hair
アドゥー！
Adieu!
オイェイ！イェイ！
Oh yay! Yay!
アッフー！
Ah-hoo!
また寝過ごしてしまいそうな
About to oversleep again
お昼テンテケテンテンテン
At noon, tenteketen-ten-ten
それピンピキピンピンピン
That pinpikipin-pin-pin
お日様が屋根に登って
The sun climbs onto the roof
遊ぶテンテケテンテンテン
To play, tenteketen-ten-ten
のんてんてん
Non-tenten
下り坂を走って
Running down the slope
信号で止まって
Stopping at the traffic light
右見て左見て
Looking right, looking left
もう一度右見て渡りましょう
Looking right once more, let's cross
今日もハレバレ
Cheerful again today
鮮やかに街は輝いている
The streets are brightly shining
キラキラと笑っている
They are smiling brilliantly
車のボンネットに移った
Reflected on the car's hood
雲が丸く流れてた
Clouds were floating in round shapes
イェーイ！
Yay!
アッフー！
Ah-hoo!
旅ゆけば　ゆけばわかるような
When you travel, as if you'd understand
気がしたならそれはいいかな
If you feel like that, is that okay?
オイェイ！イェイ！
Oh yay! Yay!
フゥー！
Fu!
夕暮れに影が伸びてゆく
The shadows stretch out in the dusk
...見守ってて
...please watch over me.
どこか弾む ラブオールの
A bouncing Love-all's...
音色が空に広がっていった
...melody spread through the sky.
はぁ〜！ということで、きょうもハレバレでした〜！
Phew! And that was "Kyou mo Harebare"!
ありがとうございました〜！
Thank you so much!
はい！ちょっとね、初めましての方もいると思うので、
最初に自己紹介をお願いしてもいいですか？
Yes! Some people might be seeing you for the first time,
so could you please introduce yourself?
お願いします！
Please go ahead!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
皆さん、こんにちは！プロプロプロダクション所属、
お菓子の星からやってきたお菓子の妖精、
Hello, everyone! I'm a candy fairy who came from
the Candy Star, belonging to ProPro Production,
甘ノ星ちろれです！
Amanohoshi Chiraree!
イェーイ！こんにちは〜！
Yay! Hello!
ちろれちゃ〜ん！ありがとう〜！
Chiraree-chan! Thank you!
ようこそ〜！
Welcome!
はい、ということでね、ちろれちゃんは、まつりがね、
ちょっとVTuberが好きで、いろいろ検索してるときに...
Right, so, I found Chiraree-chan when I was searching
around because I like VTubers...
...たまたま出会った、可愛い女です。
...and she's a cute girl I happened to come across.
ナンパされちゃいました！
I got picked up!
はい！めちゃめちゃ可愛い子で、ダンスもね、
めちゃめちゃ上手いし、
Yes! She's a super cute girl, and she's also
an amazing dancer...
そう、歌も上手でね、癒やしです。ありがとうございます。
...and a great singer too. She's so healing. Thank you.
やった〜！嬉しい、たくさん...
Yay! I'm so happy, I...
でも、会うのがちょっと2回目なんですけど、
But this is only the second time we've met.
2回目です！
Second time!
1回目会ったときにレポートを書かれまして...
When we met for the first time, she wrote
a report about me...
知る人ぞ知る、まつりに関する、
なんかご飯行ったときのレポートみたいな。
A report about me when we went to eat,
for those who know about it.
まつりちゃんもトイレに行くって書いてあった。
It said "Matsuri-chan goes to the bathroom too."
もう、絶対忘れない。
I'll never forget that.
一緒にご飯行ったときに、もう、
まつりちゃんの良いところを全部書き出そうと思って、
When we went to eat, I thought I'd write
down all of Matsuri-chan's good points...
頭の中でずっとメモしてて、で配信内に、
まつりちゃんの可愛かったところが〜って...
...so I was taking mental notes the whole time,
then in my stream I went "Here were the cute parts..."
ちょっとね、頭が、ちょっとおかしいとこもありますけど、
She's a bit... crazy in the head, but...
まあある意味ギャップ萌えということでね、
...in a way, that gap is cute.
はい、すごく大好きな子なので、今日お誕生日、
ま、7月22日が誕生日なんですけど、
Yes, I like her a lot, so I invited her today for my
birthday live, though my actual birthday is July 22nd.
今日お呼びしました！ありがト来てくれて！
Thanks for coming!
嬉しい！たくさんもう練習してきたのでね。
I'm happy! I've practiced so much.
ありがとうございます！本当に、ちょっと大変な曲ですけどもね。
Thank you! It's a pretty tough song.
いえいえ、めっちゃ楽しく踊れました！
Not at all, I had so much fun dancing!
普段もね、あの、3Dがなんと、今回で2回目！
Usually, you know, this is only her second time in 3D!
2回目！
Second time!
3Dお披露目と、これ！っていう...
Her 3D debut and this!
いいの！？
Is that okay!?
はい！今後もね、どんどん活躍していくと思うので、
あの是非、宣伝とかあればどうぞ！
Yes! I think she'll be even more active from now on,
so please, if you have anything to promote!
どうしよう、はい、え〜、宣伝か...宣伝は...
Oh boy, okay, um, promotion... promotion...
えっと、私はさっき踊ったようにダンスが大好きでして、
Well, I love dancing, as I just showed you...
どれくらいだろう、9年間ぐらいダンスをやってて、
...I've been dancing for about 9 years...
経歴では世界大会とかに出たりしてるんで、
...and I've even competed in world championships.
もし3Dとかね、多分これからダンスとか
お披露目することがあると思うんですけど、
So I'll probably be showing off my dancing
in 3D more often...
雑談も大好きなので、よかったら仲良くしてください！
...but I also love chatting, so please be friends with me!
もう3Dがどんどんね、映えていきますので、
これからに期待していきましょう！
Her 3D is going to keep looking great,
so let's look forward to it!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！嬉しい！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
じゃ、次の曲頑張ります！
Well then, I'll do my best on the next song!
頑張ってね！
Good luck!
ありがとう！
Thanks!
ありがと、またね〜！
Thanks, see you!
またね〜！
See you!
やっぱちろれちゃんいい子だったな〜。
Chiraree-chan really was a good girl.
よし！このあとも頑張れそう！
Alright! I feel like I can keep going!
みんなついてきてね！
Everyone, please keep up!
君の視線 私にください 眼差しはそのままで
Give me your gaze, keep your eyes on me just like that.
私の可愛いとこ 伝われば嬉しいです
I'll be happy if my cuteness gets through to you.
画面越しで 触れないけど 私はいるんだよ
I'm right here, even if you can't touch me through the screen.
コメントも残して 君を認知させて
Leave a comment and let me get to know you.
可愛い子なんて たくさんいるけど
There are plenty of cute girls out there...
可愛すぎる子は 私しかいない
...but there's no one as cute as me.
あざとすぎたって これが私だって
Even if I'm too calculated, this is just who I am.
君の一番になるまで やめない
I won't stop until I'm your number one.
君の大好きな人はだーれ？
Who is your favorite person?
超絶可愛い　まつり！
Super cute Matsuri!
君が愛してる人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love?
超絶可愛い　まつり！
Super cute Matsuri!
私も大好きだから
Since I love you too,
恋人同士だね
we're like lovers, aren't we?
花嫁修行
I'll do my best
頑張るね
at my bride-to-be training.
もうしばらく
Please keep up
このアピールにお付き合いください
with this appealing for a bit longer.
私の可愛いとこ
I'd be happy if my cuteness
伝われば嬉しいです
comes across to you.
心情も足のサイズも
My feelings, my shoe size,
隠れてるホクロも
even my hidden moles...
推しなら当然
if you're a fan,
知ってるはずだよね
you should naturally know them, right?
応援が大切って
That support is important
当たり前だけど
is a given, but...
こんなに好きとか
no one loves you
私しかいない
as much as I do.
空想すぎる言葉
Even words that seem like a fantasy
だって本当だもん
are true.
君の1番になるまで
I won't stop until
やめない
I become your number one.
君を虜にしたのはだーれ？
Who was it that captivated you?
超絶可愛い　まつり！
Super cute Matsuri!
君を幸せにするのはだーれ？
Who is it that makes you happy?
超絶可愛い　まつり！
Super cute Matsuri!
もっと恋してもいいよ
It's okay to fall for me more,
受け止めるからね
I'll catch you.
浮気なんて
Because I won't let you
させないから
cheat on me.
君の大好きな人はだーれ？
Who is your favorite person?
超絶可愛い　まつり！
Super cute Matsuri!
君が愛してる人はだーれ？
Who is the person you love?
超絶可愛い　まつり！
Super cute Matsuri!
私も大好きだから
Since I love you too,
恋人同士だね
we're like lovers, aren't we?
花嫁修行
I'll do my best
頑張るね
at my bride-to-be training.
まつりすー！
Matsurisu!
まつりすが一番好きなのはだーれ？
Who do Matsurisu love the most?
まつりー！
Matsuri!
えへへ
Ehehe.
まつりも、まつりすが一番大好き！
Matsuri loves Matsurisu the most too!
はい、ということで、超絶可愛いでしたー！
Alright, and that was 'Chouzetsu Kawaii'!
ゲストコーナーからソロ曲もありがとうございました！
Thank you for the guest segment and the solo song as well!
みんなどうだった？
How was it, everyone?
どうだった？可愛かったでしょ？可愛かったでしょ？
How was it? I was cute, right? I was cute, right?
いろんな子も来てくれてね
So many friends came to visit,
すごい嬉しかったね。いい誕生日になりました。
I was so happy. It's been a great birthday.
今日はね、まつりすのみんなに
Today, to show all of you
見てもらうために、知ってる人もいると思うんですけど、
Matsurisu... I think some of you might know this, but...
ダンスレッスン一日五時間あったりとか
I had dance lessons for five hours a day,
そんな中で頑張ってきました。
and I've been working hard through all that.
どうだった？
How was it?
めっちゃ良かったでしょ？
It was really good, wasn't it?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
はい、ここからね、まだまだラストスパートなんですけど、
Now then, from here, we're heading into the final stretch...
ちょっと水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water for a moment?
うわあー、よいしょ。
Ugh... There we go.
お水美味しいよ。
The water is delicious!
はい、ということでね、まつりちゃん
Okay, so, I've been doing
今日ダンスいっぱい踊ってますけどね、
a lot of dancing today, but...
このあとね、メンバー限定とかもあるんで、
After this, there's going to be a members-only segment,
絶対見逃さないように、今のうちにメンバー入っといてね！
so make sure not to miss it and join the membership now!
ということで、ここからラストスパート！
And with that, here comes the final stretch!
最後まで一緒に頑張っていきましょー！
Let's keep going strong together until the very end!
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
君の胸の奥まで届くようなメロディ奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches deep into your heart.
ハッピーシンセサイザ
作詞　作曲　編曲 / EasyPop
Happy Synthesizer
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement / EasyPop
儚く散った淡い片思い
A fleeting, faint unrequited love that scattered away.
笑い話だね　今となれば
It's just a funny story now.
見るもの全て輝いて見えた
Everything I saw seemed to shine.
あの日々が綺麗に笑ってるよ
Those days are laughing beautifully.
我慢することだけ覚えなきゃいけないの？
Do I just have to learn how to endure things?
大人になって頂戴ね
"Please grow up"—
ならなくていいよ
no, you don't have to.
知らないことばかり
So many things I don't know,
知らないなんて言えなくて
but I couldn't say I didn't know.
大変お似合いで　嘘ついてごめんね
You look great together—sorry for lying.
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
君の胸の奥まで届くようなメロディ奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches deep into your heart.
つまらない建前やヤなこと全部
I'll erase all the boring pretenses
消してあげるから　この音で
and bad things with this sound.
何の取り柄もない
For me, who has
僕にたった一つ
no saving grace, just one thing...
少しだけ出来ること
...that I can do just a little bit.
心躍らせる飾らない言葉
I'll convey unadorned words that make your heart
電子音で伝えるよ
dance through electronic sounds.
好きになること理屈なんかじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic.
理由付けなんかいらないんじゃない？
You don't need a reason, do you?
時代のせいと諦めたらそこまで
If you give up, blaming the era, that's it.
踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
You have to take a step forward or nothing will start.
ごめんね夜遅く寝るところだったでしょ
Sorry, you were probably about to sleep since it's late.
驚いた私もしようとしてた
I was surprised, I was also about to reach out.
心の裏側暴かれてるような
It feels like the back of my heart is being exposed.
惹かれあう二人に幸せな音は
For two people attracted to each other, a happy sound is...
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しくなるような
Happy synthesizer, see? It'll make you feel happy.
涙拭うメロディ奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that wipes away your tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない 別に
You don't have to act tough, you know.
自分に素直になればいい
Just be honest with yourself.
何のとりえもない 僕にただ一つ
I don't have any special talents, but there's just one thing...
少しだけできること
A small thing I can do.
そっと照れるような 単純な気持ち
Those simple feelings that make me a bit shy...
全身で伝えるよ
I'll tell them to you with my whole body.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy synthesizer, to the depths of your heart...
届くようなメロディ奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you.
つまらないことも ややこしいことも
Boring things, complicated things...
消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase them for you with this sound.
何のとりえもない 僕にただ一つ
I don't have any special talents, but there's just one thing...
少しだけできること
A small thing I can do.
心躍らせる 飾らない言葉
Unadorned words that make your heart dance...
全身で伝えるよ
I'll tell them to you with my whole body.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しくなるような
Happy synthesizer, see? It'll make you feel happy.
涙拭うメロディ奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that wipes away your tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない 別に
You don't have to act tough, you know.
自分に素直になればいい
Just be honest with yourself.
何のとりえもない 僕にただ一つ
I don't have any special talents, but there's just one thing...
少しだけできること
A small thing I can do.
そっと照れるような 単純な気持ち
Those simple feelings that make me a bit shy...
全身で伝えるよ
I'll tell them to you with my whole body.
|||トゥルティンアンテナ|||
|||Trauldin Antenna|||
ちょっとイケメンとぶつかった
Bumped into a bit of a handsome guy.
(ディンディンディンディンディンディン)
(Din din din din din din)
宿題をするのは忘れてた
I forgot to do my homework.
(ディンディンディンディンディンディン)
(Din din din din din din)
僕もマッチョになれるかな
Can I become macho too?
(ディンディンディンディンディンディン)
(Din din din din din din)
ゴミ箱に頭ぶつけた
I bumped my head on a trash can.
(ディンディンディンディンディンディン)
(Din din din din din din)
小さな溜め息つく
Sighed a little,
スキップしたらこけた
then tripped while skipping.
底立ちナマコリズム
Bottom-standing sea cucumber rhythm.
今日はどんなもりもりが釣れるのかな
I wonder what kind of "morimori" I'll catch today.
僕のことを無視したら
If you ignore me,
恋のアンテナにトロスぞ
I'll "torosu" you with my love antenna.
あちこち目を目をそらしても
Even if I look away here and there,
隙ができちゃうから
a gap will be created.
子猫のヒゲ揺らしたら
If you shake a kitten's whiskers,
二度寝したいなんて退きオール
you'll want to sleep twice, "noki ooru".
桶に詰めたチョコレート
Chocolate packed in a bucket,
欠伸をして溶けた
yawned and melted.
ボイスでされてたらぶれた
Blurred while being "buisu-ed".
(ディンディンディンディンディンディン)
(Din din din din din din)
カタツムリ遊びしてた
Was playing snails.
(ディンディンディンディンディンディン)
(Din din din din din din)
ホワイトノイズかき回す
Stirring around white noise,
鍵かけたら閉めちゃうぞ
if I lock it, I'll close it.
カレーの熊味噌汁
Curry bear miso soup.
明日はどんな漬け物が流行るのかな
I wonder what kind of pickles will be popular tomorrow.
君の心トロトロな
Tell me your heart is all mushy,
ヒトミな秘密を教えてよ
your "hitomi" secret.
ほらほら賭けを集めても
Even if you collect bets,
何も変わんないでしょ
nothing will change, right?
足跡消して上書きしては
Erase your footprints, overwrite them,
乙密で伝えるよ
and tell you with "otomitsu".
カサブタに貼ったね
Stuck it on a scab.
運命は微笑み交わし消えた
Destiny smiled, then vanished.
あいうえお どこまで やゆよ
A-I-U-E-O, how far... ya-yu-yo.
よく見て僕の話聞いて
Look closely and listen to what I have to say.
好きも嫌いもどっちだって受け止めてあげるから
Whether you like me or hate me, I'll accept it all.
トロドカミアイロベロティーノパスタ食べたいチュルチュルチュ
Trodokamiai-lo-belotino... I want to eat pasta, slurp, slurp, slurp.
迷っていたってしょうがない 今夜をうどんにしよう
It's no use being lost, let's have udon tonight.
はい！ということでみんな、ありがとう！
Yes! So, everyone, thank you!
めっちゃ可愛かったでしょ？可愛かったでしょ？
I was super cute, right? Wasn't I cute?
ということでね、やっぱライブめちゃめちゃ楽しいですね。
Anyway, lives are so much fun.
今回特にダンスいっぱい頑張ったのでね、楽しんでくれたんじゃないかなと思っておりますよ。
I worked especially hard on the dancing this time, so I hope you all enjoyed it.
ありがとうね、みんな。
Thank you, everyone.
ということで、ここからはですね、皆様お待ちかねの誕生日記念グッズ紹介！わー！
So, from here on, it's the part you've all been waiting for: the birthday memorial goods introduction! Yay!
ということで早速見ていきましょう。まずは、こちら！
So, let's take a look right away. First is this!
あ、こっち？どっち？はっ！あ、こっちかな？
Oh, this way? Which way? Hah! Oh, this way, maybe?
ということで、誕生日記念グッズですね。はい、めちゃめちゃ既にイラストが可愛いので、ぜひゲットしてください。
So, these are the birthday memorial goods. Yes, the illustrations are already super cute, so please be sure to get them.
では、一つ目見ていきましょう。
Now, let's look at the first one.
タンブラー
Tumbler
一つ目は「まつりとお揃いタンブラー」でございます。いや、花火の模様が入っててめちゃめちゃ可愛いデザインですね。
First is the "Matching Tumbler with Matsuri." It has a firework pattern and is a super cute design.
でしょ？そうでしょ？可愛いでしょ？そうなんですよ。まだちょっと暑いんで、まつりはもう手に入れているんですけども...
Right? Isn't it? It's cute, right? Exactly. It's still a bit hot, and I've already got mine, but...
あの、皆さんはまだ手に持ってないと思うんですけど、届くのはちょっと涼しくなってるかな？
...you guys don't have yours yet, so maybe it'll be cooler when it arrives?
まぁでも水分補給は大事なのでね。ゲームしてるときとか、暑くなっちゃったときとかにいっぱい飲んでください。
But hydration is important. Please drink plenty when you're gaming or when it gets hot.
何をいれてもいいですよ。水とか、ココアとか、何でも入れていいんで、いっぱい水分補給してね。
You can put anything in it. Water, cocoa, anything is fine, so stay hydrated.
そして続いてがこちら！「ライブロゴタオル」！
And next is this! "Live Logo Towel"!
ライブロゴタオル
Live Logo Towel
可愛いでしょ！今日のライブの「今夜はdance the night」、これ英語ちょっとかっこいいでしょ？のロゴが入ったタオルでございます。
Cute, right! It's a towel with the logo of today's live, "dance the night." Isn't the English a bit cool?
白井はくまい先生がデザインして下さいました。
Designed by Shirai Hakumai-sensei.
タンブラーで水分補給をして、運動したり、あとは、あの、推しのライブを見て涙拭いたりとか、
Use the tumbler for hydration while exercising, and then use this to wipe away tears while watching your favorite's live,
鼻水出したりとかした時にいっぱい拭いていただけたらと思いますよ。
or if your nose starts running, I hope you'll use it to wipe it away.
そしてそして、続いてがこちら！「ランダムアクリルキーホルダー」！
And then, next is this! "Random Acrylic Keychain"!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
Random Acrylic Keychain
いや、めっちゃ可愛い！イラストをですね、のいみね先生描き下ろしでございます。めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？
Wow, super cute! The illustrations were drawn by Noimine-sensei. Aren't they super cute?
ランダムアクキーね、実は初めてなんですよ。えー、皆さんぜひ全種類手にいれちゃってください。
Actually, it's my first time doing random acrylic keychains. Please try to collect all of them.
まぁ全部可愛いんだけど、まぁまつり特にお気に入りっていうのは...んー、まぁでも全部可愛いな。
They're all cute, but my favorite is... well, they're all cute.
でもこの衣装のやつとかも、ちょっと女の子らしかったりとか...
This one in this outfit is a bit girly...
そしてライブ衣装ですか？も、アイドル衣装も、なんか元気な感じ出てたりして、全部ね要素が違うって感じですよね。ぜひ手にいれてください。
And the live outfit? The idol outfit too, they have an energetic feel, and each has a different vibe. Please get them.
そして！こちら！「アクリルジオラマスタンド」！
And! This! "Acrylic Diorama Stand"!
アクリルジオラマスタンド
Acrylic Diorama Stand
はい！こちらはイラストはあろあ先生描き下ろしでございます。めっちゃ可愛いね！
Yes! The illustration for this was drawn by Aroa-sensei. So cute!
ライブに向けてスタジオでこうダンスレッスンを「こうかな？」頑張ってるまつりちゃんを描いていただきました。
It depicts Matsuri-chan working hard on dance lessons in the studio for the live, like "Is it like this?"
そしてですね、さっき紹介したタンブラーとタオル、それぞれをエビフライオンとまつりすが持ってくれてるんだよ。「俺もいるやで」っていう感じですね。
And, the tumbler and towel I introduced earlier, Ebifryion and Matsuris are holding them. It's like they're saying "I'm here too!"
そしてそして、これらのグッズが全部入った...
And then, a set containing all these goods...
誕生日記念フルセット
Birthday Memorial Full Set
超超超スーパー誕生日記念フルセットが販売され...され...されじゃなくて、されます！
...the super-duper-duper birthday memorial full set will be sold!
はい、あ、のあ先生描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドカードも特典として付いてきますよ。
Yes, and a cheki-style bromide card specially drawn by Anoa-sensei is also included as a bonus.
そして数量限定版あります！
And there is a limited-quantity edition!
はい、こちらフルセットのブロマイドにまつりなんと直筆サインを書いちゃいますので...
Yes, for this full set bromide, I will actually be hand-signing it...
...ぜひゲットしてください。急げ！
...so please make sure to get it. Hurry!
はい、通常版のブロマイドは箔押し、箔押し、箔、なんか分かんないけど...
Yes, the regular edition bromide has foil stamping, foil stamping, foil... I don't really know...
...なんかポンっていうなんかポンです。
...it's like, "pop," or something.
はい、皆さんぜひ手に入れてください。
Yes, everyone, please do get your hands on them.
そしてTwitterとかでもハッシュタグしてください。
And please use the hashtag on Twitter and such.
というわけで、なんと次がラストの曲になってしまいますね。
So, believe it or not, the next song will be the last one.
あ、でもラストって言っても、この後ね、メンバー限定でライブもありますよ。
Oh, but even if I say it's the last, there's a members-only live after this.
いや初めてなのメンバー限定ライブ。だからちょっとめちゃめちゃ緊張してるんですけど...
It's my first time doing a members-only live. So I'm actually really nervous...
...あの、まだ入ってないよ、でも見たいっていう人はね...
...so if you haven't joined yet but want to see it...
...もう善は急げってやつです。ぜひ見に来てください。
...as they say, there's no time like the present. Please come watch it.
ということで次歌うのは、なんとライブ初披露の曲です。頑張るぞ！
So, the next song I'm going to sing is actually its live debut. I'll do my best!
それでは聞いてください、『ばーちゃらぶ』！
Please listen, "Virtual Love"!
バーチャルリアル超えて
Transcending the virtual and the real
好きだ、もう叫びたい、伝えたいんだ
I love you, I want to shout it out, I want to tell you
うりゃおい！
Urya-oi!
あーーー！
Aaaaah!
こんにちわっしょーい！
Konnichi-wasshoi!
カバー！ネバ！サマー！カラー！フェスタ！
Cover! Never! Summer! Color! Festa!
外したイキ、不覚不意、忙しくてあたふたの毎日
Missed breath, unexpected moment, flustered and busy every day
きちゃ！こいえら！
It's here! Voice selection!
君にまつり、救われてるの
I'm being saved by you and Matsuri
まつり！俺のまつり！
Matsuri! My Matsuri!
縮む距離、慎重になった、逆らわず崇め奉りなさい
Closing the distance, I became cautious, worship me without resisting
きちゃ！赤スパ！
It's here! Red SuperChat!
限界かも、のめり込んで、どんどんデカくなっていく感情
This might be the limit, I'm falling in deep, these feelings just keep growing bigger
はーい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
おー！はい！おー！はい！おー！はい！おー！はい！
Oh! Hi! Oh! Hi! Oh! Hi! Oh! Hi!
有料、利息、お仕置き？
Fee, interest, punishment?
ごめんさっきは、嫉妬して、もらってばかりだ
Sorry for earlier, I was jealous, I'm always on the receiving end
スキスキスキスキスー
Love love love love love you
徹底、無限定、不自然肯定
Thorough, unlimited, unnatural affirmation
うおい！
Uoi!
ふわふわ
Fuwa fuwa
聞いてくれてありがとう、捧げたいんだい
Thank you for listening, I want to dedicate this to you
はいせーの！はーい！はい！はい！はい！
Ready, go! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
周年記念日も、誕生日も、一緒に祝おうね
Anniversaries and birthdays too, let's celebrate them together
おい！おい！
Oi! Oi!
バーチャルリアル超えて、好きだ、もう叫びたい、伝えたい
Transcending the virtual and the real, I love you, I want to shout it out, I want to tell you
I Love You, Love You
ハッ！ハッ！ハッ！ハッ！まつり！
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Matsuri!
ソイヤソイヤソイヤソイヤ！
Soiya soiya soiya soiya!
屈折深い、窓バイ、とりあえず全部ポチッ
Deep refraction, window buy, clicking everything for now
口癖、移りがち、生きてるって感じ
Catchphrases tend to rub off, it feels like I'm alive
肯定、模範的肯定、高まって、めでて
Affirmation, exemplary affirmation, getting excited and admiring
うおい！うおい！
Uoi! Uoi!
ふわふわ
Fuwa fuwa
これ無償でいいんですか？優勝しちゃったわ
Is it okay to have this for free? I've already won
はいせーの！はーい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Ready, go! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
狂気的な絆、先輩後輩、みんなで作って
An insane bond, seniors and juniors, creating it all together
おい！おい！
Oi! Oi!
いえー！
Yay!
温かい空間が好きだ、ずっと続いていく、見守るんだい
I love this warm space, it will continue forever, I'll keep watch
抑えきれないもう
I can't hold it back anymore
言いたいことがあるんだよ
There's something I want to say!
（なになに？）
(What is it? What is it?)
やっぱりまつりは可愛いよ
After all, Matsuri is cute!
（なになに？）
(What is it? What is it?)
好き好き大好きやっぱ好き
I love you, I love you, I really do love you!
（なになに？）
(What is it? What is it?)
やっと見つけたお姫様
I've finally found my princess!
（なになに？）
(What is it? What is it?)
俺が生まれてきた理由
The reason I was born...
（なになに？）
(What is it? What is it?)
それはお前に出会うため
...was to meet you!
（なになに？）
(What is it? What is it?)
俺と一緒に人生歩もう
Let's walk through life together!
世界で一番愛してる
I love you more than anyone in the world!
ア・イ・シ・テ・ル！
I-L-O-V-E-Y-O-U!
想い募り、重い愛、暴走仕掛けて
Feelings welling up, a heavy love, about to run wild
少し反省、改めて、今日も大好き
Reflecting a bit, starting over, I love you today too
徹底、無限定、不自然肯定
Thorough, unlimited, unnatural affirmation
うおい！
Uoi!
ふわふわ
Fuwa fuwa
聞いてくれてありがとう、捧げたいんだい
Thank you for listening, I want to dedicate this to you
はいせーの！はーい！はい！はい！はい！
Ready, go! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
周年記念日も、誕生日も、一緒に祝おうね
Anniversaries and birthdays too, let's celebrate them together
おい！おい！
Oi! Oi!
いえー！
Yay!
バーチャルリアル超えて、好きだ、もう叫びたい、伝えたい
Transcending the virtual and the real, I love you, I want to shout it out, I want to tell you
アラブーラブ、散らかして後の祭り
A love love, making a mess, the damage is done
うりゃおい！うりゃおい！
Urya-oi! Urya-oi!
あーーー！まつりわっしょーい！
Aaaaah! Matsuri-wasshoi!
カバー！ネバ！サマー！カラー！フェスタ！
Cover! Never! Summer! Color! Festa!